<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlo Cavicchia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carlo Cavicchia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-me/</guid>
      <description>current assistant professor of statistics
Econometric Institute, Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam
past research fellow of statistics
Department of Law and Economics, UnitelmaSapienza University of Rome
 education  phd in methodological statistics at La Sapienza University of Rome (2020) msc in statistics and decision sciences at La Sapienza University of Rome (2016) bsc in statistics at La Sapienza University of Rome (2013)  grants  research grant for junior researcher &amp;ldquo;Avvio alla ricerca&amp;rdquo; (2017) award in Italian Statistical Society (SIS) competition: best report (2017)  academic services  programme committee member of the conference &amp;ldquo;IES 2021: Innovation and Society 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>codes</title>
      <link>/codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/codes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>email cavicchia@ese.eur.nl
 personal page dr. Carlo Cavicchia
 address Room ET-02, P.O. Box 1738, 3000 DR Rotterdam, The Netherlands
Tel. +31 010 4081253</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>events</title>
      <link>/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/</guid>
      <description>future conferences:  24th Internation Conference on Computational Statistics (August 29-31, 2021) 17th onference of the International Federation of Classification Societies (August 24-28, 2021) 63rd ISI World Statistics Congress 2021 (July 11-16, 2021) Data Science, Statistics &amp;amp; Visualization 2021 (July 07-09, 2021) Innovation and Society 5.0: Statistical and Economic Models and Techniques for Quality Assessment (July 01-02, 2021) 50th Scientific Meeting of the Italian Statistical Society (June 23-25, 2021)   recent events  Workshop on Models and Learning for Clustering and Classification (September 2020) Data Science, Statistics &amp;amp; Visualization 2020 (July 29-31, 2020)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ongoing projects</title>
      <link>/ongoing_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ongoing_projects/</guid>
      <description>my current researches are:
  Cavicchia, C. and Vichi, M.
Second-Order Disjoint Exploratory Factor Analysis
a new latent factor model called Second-order Disjoint Exploratory Factor Analysis in order to model an unknown hierarchical structure of the manifest variables with two orders. It is an exploratory second-order factor analysis, which is nested and estimated simultaneously by maximum likelihood method via a cyclic block coordinate descent algorithm. (Submitted)
  Cavicchia, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>I am a statistician and my research is focused on the methodological and computational aspects of data analysis. The best feeling is when I can use my knowledge to solve pratical and real problems. I am currently working on latent variable models, unsupervised classification and model-based composite indicators.
ongoing projects events teaching material </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>journal articles   Cavicchia, C., Vichi, M. and Zaccaria, G. (2020)
The ultrametric correlation matrix for modelling hierarchical latent concepts.
Advances in Data Analysis and Classification, doi
  Cavicchia, C., Sarnacchiaro, P. and Vichi, M. (2020)
A composite indicator for the waste management in the EU via Hierarchical Disjoint Non-Negative Factor Analysis.
Socio-Economic Planning Sciences, doi
  Cavicchia, C., and Vichi, M. (2020)
Statistical Model-based Composite Indicators for tracking coherent policy conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching material</title>
      <link>/teaching_material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching_material/</guid>
      <description>courses and material  this year I have supervised bsc theses at Erasmus School of Economics on the following papers:  Vichi and Kiers (2001) Bluszcz (2016)       the last two years I taught pratical classes during the Statistics course for bsc students at LUISS University of Rome
 material: one; two; three; answers one answers two answers three    this year I taught pratical classes during the Statistics course for bsc students at LUISS University of Rome</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>