<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlo Cavicchia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carlo Cavicchia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-me/</guid>
      <description>current assistant professor of statistics
Econometric Institute, Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam
past research fellow of statistics
Department of Law and Economics, UnitelmaSapienza University of Rome
 education  phd in methodological statistics at La Sapienza University of Rome (2020) msc in statistics and decision sciences at La Sapienza University of Rome (2016) bsc in statistics at La Sapienza University of Rome (2013)  grants  research grant for junior researcher &amp;ldquo;Avvio alla ricerca&amp;rdquo; (2017) award in Italian Statistical Society (SIS) competition: best report (2017)  academic services  session organizer and chair of the 50th edition of the Scientific Meeting of the Italian Statistical Society (2020) reviewer for Journal of Statistical Computation and Simulation reviewer for Advances in Data Analysis and Classification  memberships  Società Italiana di Statistica - Italian Statistical Society (SIS) Classification and Data Analysis Group (CLADAG) Statistica per la Valutazione e la Qualità nei Servizi (SVQS)   extra  addicted to ASD Valcanneto Fustal and ice-cream  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>codes</title>
      <link>/codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/codes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>email cavicchia@ese.eur.nl
 personal page \
 address Room \ , P.O. Box 1738, 3000 DR Rotterdam, The Netherlands</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>events</title>
      <link>/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/</guid>
      <description>future conferences:  50th edition of the Scientific Meeting of the Italian Statistical Society (June 2020) [CANCELED]   recent events  ASA 2019 Scientific Conference on Statistics for Healt and Well-Being (September 2019) 12nd Scientific Meeting of Classification and Data Analysis Group (September 2019)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ongoing projects</title>
      <link>/ongoing_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ongoing_projects/</guid>
      <description>my current researches are:
  Cavicchia, C. and Vichi, M.
Second-Order Disjoint Exploratory Factor Analysis
a new latent factor model called Second-order Disjoint Exploratory Factor Analysis in order to model an unknown hierarchical structure of the manifest variables with two orders. It is an exploratory second-order factor analysis, which is nested and estimated simultaneously by maximum likelihood method via a cyclic block coordinate descent algorithm.
  Cavicchia, C., Vichi, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>I am a statistician and my research is focused on the methodological and computational aspects of data analysis. The best feeling is when I can use my knowledge to solve pratical and real problems. I am currently working on latent variable models, unsupervised classification and model-based composite indicators.
ongoing projects events codes teaching material </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>journal articles   Cavicchia, C., Vichi, M. and Zaccaria, G. (2020)
The ultrametric correlation matrix for modelling hierarchical latent concepts.
Advances in Data Analysis and Classification, doi
  Cavicchia, C., Sarnacchiaro, P. and Vichi, M. (2020)
A composite indicator for the waste management in the EU via Hierarchical Disjoint Non-Negative Factor Analysis.
Socio-Economic Planning Sciences, doi
  Cavicchia, C., and Vichi, M. (2020)
Statistical Model-based Composite Indicators for tracking coherent policy conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching material</title>
      <link>/teaching_material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching_material/</guid>
      <description>courses and material  during the last two years I have taught the Preparatory Course in Statistics for the msc courses in European Economy and Business Law at Torvergata University of Rome  material: one; two; three; four; five      this year I did pratical classes during the Statistics course for bsc students at LUISS University of Rome  material: one; two; three; four      this year I looked after the SAS lab for the Business Statistics course for bsc students at Torvergata University of Rome  material: one; two; three; four    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>