<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlo Cavicchia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carlo Cavicchia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-me/</guid>
      <description>current assistant professor of statistics
Econometric Institute, Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam
past research fellow of statistics
Department of Law and Economics, UnitelmaSapienza University of Rome
 education  dutch university teaching qualification (BKO) Risbo - Erasmus University Rotterdam (2022) phd in methodological statistics at La Sapienza University of Rome (2020) msc in statistics and decision sciences at La Sapienza University of Rome (2016) bsc in statistics at La Sapienza University of Rome (2013)  qualifications  National Qualification for Associate Professor (Italy, ASN II fascia), Statistics (SC 13/D1, June-2023)  awards and grants  ESE starter grant (300000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>codes</title>
      <link>/codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/codes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>email cavicchia@ese.eur.nl
 personal page dr. Carlo Cavicchia
 address Room ET-02, P.O. Box 1738, 3000 DR Rotterdam, The Netherlands
Tel. +31 010 4081253</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>events</title>
      <link>/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/</guid>
      <description>future conferences  Workshop on Statistical Computing and Robust Inference for High Dimensional Data (December 10-14, 2023 - Taipei, Taiwan)   recent events  ISI 2023: 64th ISI World Statistics Congress (July 16-20, 2023 - Ottawa, Canada) DSSV-ECDA 2023: Joint conference of Data Science, Statistics &amp;amp; Visualisation and the European Conference on Data Analysis (July 05-07, 2023 - Antwerp, Belgium) SIS 2023: 52nd Scientific Meeting of the Italian Statistical Society (June 21-23, 2023 - Ancona, Italy) 11th VOC conference (June 02, 2023 - Rotterdam, Netherlands) CMStatistics 2022: 15th International Conference of the ERCIM WG on Computational and Methodological Statistics (December 17-19, 2022 - London, UK)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>materials and info</title>
      <link>/materials-and-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/materials-and-info/</guid>
      <description>I am a statistician and my research is focused on the methodological and computational aspects of data analysis. The best feeling is when I can use my knowledge to solve practical and real problems. I am currently working on latent variable models, unsupervised classification and model-based composite indicators.
ongoing projects software seminars and talks events teaching </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ongoing projects</title>
      <link>/ongoing_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ongoing_projects/</guid>
      <description>my current research consists of:
  A general framework for implementing distance functions for categorical variables (van de Velden, M., Iodice D&amp;rsquo;Enza, A., Markos, A. and Cavicchia, C.) - Under review, arXiv, SSRN
  A new ranking calculation based on a composite indicator model: the case of the top 20 European football teams (Cavicchia, C. and Sarnacchiaro, P.) - Under review
  Parsimonious Gaussian mixture models with extended ultrametric covariance structures (Cavicchia, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>refereed journal articles   Cavicchia, C., Sarnacchiaro, P., Vichi, M. and Zaccaria, G.
A model-based ultrametric composite indicator for studying waste management in Italian municipalities
Computational Statistics, (2023+)
  Vichi, M., Cavicchia, C. and Groenen, P.J.F.
Hierarchical Means Clustering
Journal of Classification, 39(3), pp.553–577 (2022)
  Cavicchia, C., Vichi, M. and Zaccaria, G.
Hierarchical Disjoint Principal Component Analysis
AStA Advances in Statistical Analysis, (2022)
  Cavicchia, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>seminars and talks</title>
      <link>/talks_and_seminars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks_and_seminars/</guid>
      <description>seminars and invited talks   Ultrametric Gaussian Mixture models with parsimonious structures - ISI 2023: International Statistical Institute World Statistics Congress (2023 - Ottawa, Canada)
  A composite indicator for circular economy performance - ISI 2023: International Statistical Institute World Statistics Congress (2023 - Ottawa, Canada)
  Convex Clustering of Mixed Numerical and Categorical Data - DSSV-ECDA 2023: Joint conference of Data Science, Statistics &amp;amp; Visualisation and the European Conference on Data Analysis (2023 - Antwerp, Belgium)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>software</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description>I am the author and contributor of the following R package:
 catdist  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>supervisions   in the last few years I have been supervising ten msc theses in Econometrics (on mixed-type data clustering methods and machine learning methods for econometrics), ten msc theses in Data Science for Marketing Analytics (on supervised machine learning methods), and twenty-four bsc theses in Econometrics (on Witten and Tibshirani (2010), Cavicchia, Vichi and Zaccaria (2022), Adachi and Trendafilov (2018), Vichi and Kiers (2001) and Bluszcz (2016)) at Erasmus School of Economics</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>